<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Discover Mauritius5</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="d_mm_yyyy"><font color="#808080">D-MM-YYYY</font></string>
    <string name="_mm_yyyy"><font color="#808080">-MM-YYYY</font></string>
    <string name="m_yyyy"><font color="#808080">M-YYYY</font></string>
    <string name="_yyyy"><font color="#808080">-YYYY</font></string>
    <string name="yyyy"><font color="#808080">YYYY</font></string>
    <string name="yyy"><font color="#808080">YYY</font></string>
    <string name="yy"><font color="#808080">YY</font></string>
    <string name="y"><font color="#808080">Y</font></string>
    <string name="the_island_of_mauritius_was_uninhabited_before_its_first_recorded_visit_by_arab_sailors_in_the_end_of_the_10th_century_its_name_dina_arobi_has_been_associated_with_arab_sailors_who_first_discovered_the_island_nthe_treaty_of_tordesillas_purported_to_give_the_kingdom_of_portugal_the_right_to_colonise_this_part_of_the_world_in_1507_portuguese_sailors_came_to_the_uninhabited_island_and_established_a_visiting_base_diogo_fernandes_pereira_a_portuguese_navigator_was_the_first_european_known_to_land_in_mauritius_he_named_the_island_ilha_do_cisne_island_of_the_swan_the_portuguese_did_not_stay_long_as_they_were_not_interested_in_these_islands_the_mascarene_islands_were_named_after_pedro_mascarenhas_viceroy_of_portuguese_india_after_his_visit_to_the_islands_in_1512_rodrigues_island_was_named_after_portuguese_explorer_diogo_rodrigues_who_first_came_upon_the_island_in_1528_nin_1598_a_dutch_squadron_under_admiral_wybrand_van_warwyck_landed_at_grand_port_and_named_the_island_mauritius_after_prince_maurice_of_nassau_dutch_maurits_van_nassau_of_the_dutch_republic_the_dutch_inhabited_the_island_in_1638_from_which_they_exploited_ebony_trees_and_introduced_sugar_cane_domestic_animals_and_deer_it_was_from_here_that_dutch_navigator_abel_tasman_set_out_to_seek_the_great_southern_land_mapping_parts_of_tasmania_new_zealand_and_new_guinea_the_first_dutch_settlement_lasted_20_years_in_1639_the_dutch_east_india_company_brought_enslaved_malagasy_to_cut_down_ebony_trees_and_to_work_in_the_new_tobacco_and_sugar_cane_plantations_several_attempts_to_establish_a_colony_permanently_were_subsequently_made_but_the_settlements_never_developed_enough_to_produce_dividends_causing_the_dutch_to_abandon_mauritius_in_1710_a_1755_article_in_the_english_leeds_intelligencer_claims_that_the_island_was_abandoned_due_to_the_large_number_of_long_tailed_macaque_monkeys_which_destroyed_everything_in_it_and_that_it_was_also_known_at_the_time_as_the_island_of_monkeys_portuguese_sailors_had_brought_these_monkeys_to_the_island_from_their_native_habitat_in_southeast_asia_prior_to_dutch_rule">The island of Mauritius was uninhabited before its first recorded visit by Arab sailors in the end of the 10th century. Its name Dina Arobi has been associated with Arab sailors who first discovered the island. \nThe Treaty of Tordesillas purported to give the Kingdom of Portugal the right to colonise this part of the world. In 1507, Portuguese sailors came to the uninhabited island and established a visiting base. Diogo Fernandes Pereira, a Portuguese navigator, was the first European known to land in Mauritius. He named the island Ilha do Cisne (Island of the Swan). The Portuguese did not stay long as they were not interested in these islands. The Mascarene Islands were named after Pedro Mascarenhas, Viceroy of Portuguese India, after his visit to the islands in 1512. Rodrigues Island was named after Portuguese explorer Diogo Rodrigues, who first came upon the island in 1528. \nIn 1598, a Dutch squadron under Admiral Wybrand Van Warwyck landed at Grand Port and named the island Mauritius after Prince Maurice of Nassau (Dutch: Maurits van Nassau) of the Dutch Republic. The Dutch inhabited the island in 1638, from which they exploited ebony trees and introduced sugar cane, domestic animals and deer. It was from here that Dutch navigator Abel Tasman set out to seek the Great Southern Land, mapping parts of Tasmania, New Zealand and New Guinea. The first Dutch settlement lasted 20 years. In 1639, the Dutch East India Company brought enslaved Malagasy to cut down ebony trees and to work in the new tobacco and sugar cane plantations. Several attempts to establish a colony permanently were subsequently made, but the settlements never developed enough to produce dividends, causing the Dutch to abandon Mauritius in 1710. A 1755 article in the English Leeds Intelligencer claims that the island was abandoned due to the large number of long tailed macaque monkeys which destroyed everything in it, and that it was also known at the time as the Island of Monkeys. Portuguese sailors had brought these monkeys to the island from their native habitat in Southeast Asia, prior to Dutch rule.</string>
</resources>